<?xml version="1.0"?><page><version date="6/12/2005" time="6:00:00 pm" user="Je77" /><settings><s name="lock" type="boolean">false</s></settings><name>The Architecture</name><text>!To Edit Addresses, Templates, Actions, etc.#Start the server (using the ComSwiki Launcher)#Bring up the window menu for the SwikiBrowser#-This is done by pressing the icon next to the X button#Select 'open swiki browser...'Updates made in the SwikiBrowser will take immediate effect.!Addresses-addresses are smalltalk blocks-for instance, swiki/4.edit has an 'edit' address-request, response, shelf, book and page are sent to the 'edit' page address and what returns is the page content (a string)-addresses are compiled and loaded into memory at startup!Templates-templates are the HTML files which are used by the addresses to display information-for instance, the default template (for viewing) is 'view' (page since it is only to be used for pages)-templates call actions by having the name of the action surrounded by '&amp;lt;?' and '?&amp;gt;'--for instance, '&amp;lt;?bookName?&amp;gt;' maps to '(book pages at: 1) showName'--a book template can only call book actions--a page template can call both book and page actions-templates are loaded into memory at startup!Actions-actions are smalltalk blocks called by templates to add functionality-a book action receives request, response, shelf and book-a page action receives request, response, shelf, book and page-actions are compiled and loaded into memory at startup!Setup-the 'setup.xml' file contains the information that the shelf will need to know to initialize that specific book.-setup is not inherited!Settings-the 'settings.xml' file contains the static objects that the Swiki will need to run, such as formatter, color scheme, file locations, etc.-these settings are compiled and loaded into memory at startup-settings are inherited!Shelf-the shelf is the place where the requests come in. The shelf decides whether the request should be processed by a book or by itself.!Books-the book holds the pages.-the settings for the book are values it uses during processing and can be altered.-the modules are things that are created at run time (usually through the initialize priv address) and are not stored.!Pages-the pages are processed at startup (text and old versions are not loaded into memory for memory conservation)-do NOT edit pages manually while the server is running since this can cause serious problems</text></page>